To protect and serve the living.
R.I.P.D. is a fantasy, action, comedy film directed by Robert Schwentke.
A recently slain cop joins a team of undead police officers working for the Rest
in Peace Department and tries to find the man who murdered him.
Roy Pulsipher, played by Jeff Bridges.
Nick Walker, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Bobby Hayes, played by Kevin Bacon.
Proctor, played by Mary-Louise Parker.
Julia, played by Stephanie Szostak.
Nawlicki, played by Robert Knepper.
R.I.P.D.: Rest in Peace Department, or simply R.I.P.D., is a 2013 American
supernatural action comedy film starring Jeff Bridges and Ryan Reynolds.
The film was directed by Robert Schwentke and written by Phil Hay and
Matt Manfredi based on the 1999 comic book R.I.P.D.
by Peter M.
The film also stars Kevin Bacon, Mary-Louise Parker,
Stéphanie Szostak, and Marisa Miller.
Filming was completed on January 28, 2012, and the film was originally set to be released on June 28,
2013 in the United States by Universal Pictures, but was pushed back to July 19, 2013.
The film was a box-office bomb, grossing $78.3 million on a $130‒154 million
budget, and received generally negative reviews from critics.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray on October 29, 2013.
A direct-to-video prequel, R.I.P.D.
2: Rise of the Damned, was released on November 15, 2022.
The film explores themes of gold, wife, detective,
investigation, police operation.
The tone is lighthearted.